## Behvandi Amir

Birthday: 28-08-1983 Marriage status: not married

E-mail: Amirbehvandi747@gmail.com

Mobile: +98 936 781 73 25

Skype: amir.behvandi747

Address:

No.5 West Lahel Alley, North Shahin, Tehran Iran.

Linkedin.com: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/amir-behvandi/25/a57/566



## **Profile**

Self-motivated when I succeed, persuasive, convincing, nice treatment, fluidness conversational, proactive, and excellent with open public relationship, expert in computational experience skills. I am hard working and very determined. I enjoy keeping myself busy and put extra effort in my tasks. I enjoy working with other and able to work unsupervised. I have excellent communication skills and telephone techniques.

I am reliable, I strive to always keep a positive attitude and have the ability to learn quickly.

As my basic functions I consider to have in me cultural team work as quality and culture on productivity, domain of techniques and strategies in selling pacifications and the most important to work on determination of goals.

# **Technical Skills**

Skill	Level	Certificate	
Python	Advanced	-	
Django	Advanced	-	
PHP	Advanced	-	
Laravel	Advanced		
.Net	Advanced	Yes	
Android app development	Intermediate	Yes	
iPhone app development	Intermediate	Yes	
SQL Server	enough knowledge for OOP	-	
	programming		
mySQL	enough knowledge for OOP	-	
	programming		
SEO	Intermediate	-	
Network+	Advanced	Yes	
CCNA	Intermediate	Yes	
PLC	Intermediate	Yes	
Javascript	Enough knowledge for OOP	-	
	programming		
HTML	Advanced	-	
CSS	Advanced	-	
MS Share point designer	Intermediate	Yes	

MVC	Intermediate	Yes
SOAP and REST	Intermediate	
Crystal Reports	Advanced	-
Adobe Design Review API	Advanced	-
Programming		
Agile/Scrum	Intermediate	-
AngularJS	Beginner	-
UML	Intermediate	
JavaScript	Intermediate	-

# Language Skills

	Reading	Writing	Speaking
English	Advance	Advance	Advance
Persian	Native	Native	Native
Armenian	-	Intermediate	Intermediate

## Summery

Analytical, systematic, efficient and independent. Enjoy discovering new technologies and learn easily. Sociable and thrive on working with other talented people. I love creating awesome .Net ,C#,C++ Windows base applications based on a solid architecture.

During my field in the IT industry I have had a wide exposure to various programming languages and always willing to further develop my skills in Database (SQL Server 2008).

I am keen to participate in the analysis, design and implementation stages of the PIMS & IDMS. I am self-motivated and will work well as part of a team or independently.

Senior Web Developer working on a wide range of web projects. Most projects were based on Wordpress CMS,PHP ,HTML ,CSS. Some examples include www.twi.ir and www.tamtechco.com

# **Employment**

# IT Manager & Software Developper

Kalasoda

# **Senior Software Developer**

TWI Central Asia

December 2011 – Present (5 years )

Database developing, Software developing for PIMS & IDMS & Corrosion Management System, Network designing and network administration, SQL Server 2008 Management, Crystal Reports

- Developing Andriod application for United Corors of Bipolars in Persian language and publish it on café Bazar Online Market. Download link: <a href="https://cafebazaar.ir/app/com.example.amir.bipolardisordertest/?l=fa">https://cafebazaar.ir/app/com.example.amir.bipolardisordertest/?l=fa</a>
- Developing Andriod application for United Corors of Bipolars(bipolar disorder test) and publish it on Google Play Download link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ucbp.example.amir.bipolardisordertest
- · Developing 3D modeling presenter of IDMS!

I have developed a software which can get 3D modeling file like NavisWorks and DWF from PDMS or result of Laser Scanning and assign a unique ID to each component, with the help of the ID program change transport the object,

Like changing color or moving it. With the help of LINQ The program connects to SQL server with is filled by data of inspection and then change the colors of object according to their remaining life or risk assessment( the same color as risk matrix).

Developing a software for representing result of structure assessment platforms for Iranian Offshore Oil Company.

I have used Microsoft Visual Studio 2010.

#### · Development of Intranet

AS our company needed to have an intranet for employees to enter their timesheets online and generating different kind of reports for managers, I begun to develop at intranet for our company.

Actually I chose PHP for coding because I know it every good and it's syntaxes are similar to C# And used HTML and CSS for designing the interface on web. Instead Mysql I used SQL server as my database because I was planning to connect my database to a windows application management consul for managers to get required reports from employees timesheets for this step I used C#.

- Developing a software for representing result of structure assessment platforms for National Iranian South Oil Company. I have used Microsoft Visual Studio 2010 and Microsoft SQL server 2008.
- Developing Software for Corrosion Management System for National Iranian Offshore Oil company. Actually i
  developed the software with the help of C# and i used SQL server 2008 as database and also i embedded DWG
  true viewer for showing Isometric plan of platforms and DWF design review to show 3D models of platforms and
  also i embedded Crystal Reports Viewer to generate reports, i could create specific reports with writing queries in
  SQL and use them in Crystal reports, the software could be install on different PCs and can be connected to a
  single SQL server in a local or public network, the SQL server play role as file server to store Isometrics and 3D
  Models DWF files.
- Corrosion Rate Calculating Application for Oil and Gas Industry i developed the software with the help of C# and WPF, Actually with WPF i could design very nice and attractive interface and then i did back end coding in C#.
- Developing android application for tablets and other devices to represents any piping systems assessment result Which can be connected to the main sql server and receives datas.

• Developing a software which can control hardware by sending signal throw Parallel port, I have developed the Software with the help of C++ languages

# IT Manager

#### TWI Central Asia

December 2011 – Present (5 Years)

- Accomplishes information technology staff results by communicating job expectations; planning, monitoring, and appraising job results; coaching, counseling, and disciplining employees; initiating, coordinating, and enforcing systems, policies, and procedures.
- Maintains staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees; maintaining a safe and secure work environment; developing personal growth opportunities.
- Maintains organization's effectiveness and efficiency by defining, delivering, and supporting strategic plans for implementing information technologies.
- Directs technological research by studying organization goals, strategies, practices, and user projects.
- Completes projects by coordinating resources and timetables with user departments and data center.
- Verifies application results by conducting system audits of technologies implemented.
- Preserves assets by implementing disaster recovery and back-up procedures and information security and control structures.
- Recommends information technology strategies, policies, and procedures by evaluating organization outcomes; identifying problems; evaluating trends; anticipating requirements.
- Accomplishes financial objectives by forecasting requirements; preparing an annual budget; scheduling expenditures; analyzing variances; initiating corrective action.
- Maintains quality service by establishing and enforcing organization standards.
- Maintains professional and technical knowledge by attending educational workshops; reviewing professional publications; establishing personal networks; benchmarking state-of-the-art practices; participating in professional societies.
- Contributes to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed.

## GreenWays Computers - General Manager 2008 - 2011 Georgia (Tbilisi)

- Organization Selling Computers and IT Equipment.
- Manage Sales, and maintain customer relations.
- · Stock inventory and Accounts handling.
- Managing staff.

## NS Trans - Transport Manager 2006 – 2008 Armenia (Yerevan)

- · Forwarding Containers and air cargo in Middle East.
- Survey and packaging of goods.
- Interpreter: English Persian
- Coordinate business through Middle East.
- Sales related to cargos via Iran.

Caree

## ACE Forwarding Caspian LTD, Georgia (Tbilisi)

• IT manager,  $\subseteq$  Design Software for the Organization.

#### Oxin Yadak, Iran, Ahwaz 2 0 0 3 to 2005

Organized own independent Auto-mobile spare parts shop. **\( \sigma\)** Fully managed and maintained the shop.

# **Educational Background**

## State Engineering University of Armenia

- Computer Software Engineering and Automated Systems (Yerevan-Armenia 2006-2010).
- College at European academic university of Armenia (Yerevan-Armenia 2005).
- Mechanical Engineering at Azad University(Dezful-Iran 2002-2004).
- Elmamouzan High School (Ahvaz-Iran 1998-2002)

### skills:

## Sports

- Motor Racing: Rally Car racing 2 years
- Hockey: inline-skates hoc key: 3 years from 1998 2001
   Lawn Tennis: 2 years. ot Licenses for: Para-Gliding:
- Flityninegss: and bodybuildingA chieved Club Pil Hiking

### References

Available on request.